<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Exeal</title><link>https://www.exeal.com/en/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Exeal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es-es</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 16:14:05 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.exeal.com/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Foundation of Continuous Integration: Micro-Commits</title><link>https://www.exeal.com/en/blog/2023/12/the-foundation-of-continuous-integration-micro-commits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.exeal.com/en/blog/2023/12/the-foundation-of-continuous-integration-micro-commits/</guid><description>You might be surprised (it surprised me when I began helping other teams as a coach), but most developers commit code to version control only about 2 or 3 times a week.
This limits the frequency with which they can deliver working code to production.
When our goal is to increase the frequency of delivering value and, therefore, practice trunk-based development, continuous integration, and continuous delivery, we seek the opposite: to accelerate the frequency of our commits, as much as possible.</description></item><item><title>Deliberate Practice: An Alternative Way to Learn TDD</title><link>https://www.exeal.com/en/blog/2023/10/deliberate-practice-an-alternative-way-to-learn-tdd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.exeal.com/en/blog/2023/10/deliberate-practice-an-alternative-way-to-learn-tdd/</guid><description>Have you ever found yourself stuck while practicing TDD, refactoring, software design, or any other programming-related skill?
Do you feel like you&amp;rsquo;ve run out of katas to solve, and the ones available are too simple?
Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s because you&amp;rsquo;re practicing with the wrong approach.
To get the most out of practicing with katas, we need to employ a very specific practice technique: deliberate practice.
What is deliberate practice? Deliberate practice is a method for practicing any skill, especially those that require repetition to master a technique.</description></item><item><title>How to write the first test using TDD</title><link>https://www.exeal.com/en/blog/2023/10/how-to-write-the-first-test-using-tdd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.exeal.com/en/blog/2023/10/how-to-write-the-first-test-using-tdd/</guid><description>The first test is one of the most important steps when we develop using TDD. It&amp;rsquo;s the one that will determine whether we build our solution on solid foundations or unnecessarily complicate our lives.
There are three main things I ask of my first test:
Firstly, it should lay out the most important elements that will come into play, or the inputs and outputs of the system (a.k.a. the simplest &amp;ldquo;given&amp;rdquo;).</description></item></channel></rss>